<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luís Pedro Fonseca</title>
    <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Luís Pedro Fonseca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity VR Joystick</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-vr-joystick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-vr-joystick/</guid>
      <description>For the past year, I have become more and more interested in virtual reality, especially after trying out a bunch of demos at the last Unite in LA. So much, in fact, that I have decided to go ahead and buy an HTC Vive. Being a new technology, it is still quite expensive, not only because of the price of the device itself but also because you need to have a pretty beefy PC to support it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unite Los Angeles 16</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unite-los-angeles-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unite-los-angeles-16/</guid>
      <description>It was with great pleasure and pride that I learnt that ProCamera2D got nominated to this year&amp;rsquo;s Unity Awards! The award cerimony took place in Los Angeles, on the first evening of the Unite 16 conference.
Unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t win, but being a finalist was more than I ever expected. The winner was Dungeon Architect. Congratulations to Code Respawn and all the other nominees! They were all amazing and I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to be part of this group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Custom Rect Editor</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-custom-rect-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-custom-rect-editor/</guid>
      <description>One of the main goals of ProCamera2D&amp;rsquo;s new extension - Rooms - was to make it as user-friendly as possible.
Each room is basically a rectangle with some extra data to allow custom transitions. To make it easy to edit the rooms the user should be able to interact with them on the scene. However, Unity does not have a built-in rectangle (Rect) editor tool.
Gladly, Unity is very flexible and easy to extend, so I created a simple one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site engine — Hugo</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/new-site-engine-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/new-site-engine-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started with this blog/website, publishing a new post, updating some information or even tweaking its layout, has always been a chore.
This website was made with Wordpress because that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the standard when you&amp;rsquo;re planning to start a blog. Your host provider gives you a very convenient one-click install solution and you can be up and running in a matter of minutes. There are an infinite number of plugins for every possible use-case you can think of and even more themes to customize its look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProCamera2D at GDC16</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-at-gdc16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-at-gdc16/</guid>
      <description>This year I had the honor to be invited to be part of the biggest game development conference in the world — the Game Developers Conference in San Francisco. The invite came from Unity and they were kind enough to offer me a kiosk, inside their gigantic mega-booth, where I could showcase my Unity camera plugin - ProCamera2D.
I also got two Expo passes for the 3 days and I even got to attend Unity&amp;rsquo;s own keynote at the Intercontinental hotel (amazing breakfast included!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProCamera2D turns 1!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-turns-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 09:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-turns-1/</guid>
      <description>My first commit for ProCamera2D was almost exactly 1 year ago, on January 20th 2015. It was officially released 6 months later.
Although it may sound weird to celebrate this, instead of the release date, for me it really marks a turning point. On that day I decided I was going to release my own product, no matter what, after years and years of exclusively working on clients&amp;rsquo; projects.
While I still work on clients&amp;rsquo; projects and I thoroughly enjoy it, there&amp;rsquo;s a deeper and more meaningful connection when the success and direction of a project is 100% under your responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Unity iOS Game Development — Technical review</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/learning-unity-ios-game-development-technical-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 11:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/learning-unity-ios-game-development-technical-review/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I got in my mailbox a book I technically reviewed for Packt. It&amp;rsquo;s a great feeling having a book with your name on it, even if not on the front page. 😀
As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably guessed, it&amp;rsquo;s about Unity and iOS publishing. Although you won&amp;rsquo;t find anything particularly new in there, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice package, has a few good examples and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint you. It&amp;rsquo;s a good gift for that game dev friend of yours who is just getting started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Unity plugin is here!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/my-first-unity-plugin-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/my-first-unity-plugin-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Hi all, long time no talk.
For the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly busy between client work and working on my first Unity plugin. This plugin started out as a little tool that I extracted from Project Cuba, but ended up becoming a full-fledged 2D camera solution so I decided to turn it into a plugin and put it on the Asset Store.
  It ended up taking up a lot more time than I expected due to all the work I wasn&amp;rsquo;t anticipating, mostly marketing related.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Workshop</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 23:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Past month I received an invitation to give an Unity workshop at the prestigious University of Minho, located in the beautiful city of Braga. The invitation came from the extremely welcoming guys at CeSIUM, who were organising a week of events related to computer engineering.
Gladly I got a packed room with over 60 people eager to know more about Unity! This really shows how Unity is getting into the hands of users at very early stages and how the indie scene is growing in Portugal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview to CreativeBloq</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/interview-to-creativebloq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 14:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/interview-to-creativebloq/</guid>
      <description>The nice guys at CreativeBloq contacted me to do an interview regarding my creative process, more specifically about how I used Affinity Designer on Project Cuba to speed up my development.
Take a look here and let me know your thoughts! 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Unity mobile icons</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/create-unity-mobile-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 16:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/create-unity-mobile-icons/</guid>
      <description>If you work with Unity for mobile you know the pain of creating all the required icon sizes. That&amp;rsquo;s why I created a service for OS X (sorry Windows users), that with a simple right-click on a PNG gives you the option to create and conveniently name them.
Just select a large PNG of your icon, right-click, and then under _Services_ you&amp;rsquo;ll find Create Unity Mobile Icons.
To install, download this zip file and double-click the workflow file inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New tool — New character!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/new-tool-new-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 17:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/new-tool-new-character/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I wrote about why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t renewing my Adobe subscription. At that time, I was planning to replace Photoshop and Illustrator with Pixelmator and iDraw, respectively. One month later, everything still stands, but those like me, who have been considering a change for a long time, now have one more VERY strong reason to do so.
A couple of weeks ago, while on vacation, I was checking my Twitter feed and someone shared a video about a new software that just got released on the App Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Cuba Main Character progress</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/project-cuba-main-character-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 21:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/project-cuba-main-character-progress/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was digging through some of my files and found the various iterations of Jack, the main character of my upcoming game, Project Cuba.
While the process itself was fairly simple and quick I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth to share because it shows a different approach of the typical process. Since my hand drawing skills are very limited I opted to jump straight into Illustrator. While this is probably a lot slower for someone that knows how to put their thoughts in paper and only then trace them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Cuba First Audio Test</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/project-cuba-first-audio-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 15:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/project-cuba-first-audio-test/</guid>
      <description>While at this point I&amp;rsquo;d like to be showing you some Project Cuba gameplay, the truth is that progress on that regard has been slower than expected. I&amp;rsquo;ve been super busy with some client projects and when I do have some time, there&amp;rsquo;s still plenty to do before my perfectionist self puts some gameplay out there. But please don&amp;rsquo;t despair, it&amp;rsquo;s coming soon! 😁
However, this week I&amp;rsquo;m bringing you the first musical piece for the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spine IK is here!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/spine-ik-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 21:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/spine-ik-is-here/</guid>
      <description>One of the coolest features for Spine is finally ready for prime-time. The inverse kinematics (IK) has been in the works for a few months already but it&amp;rsquo;s now available in the editor and on a wide range of the supported runtimes.
  For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve only been doing some quick tests but I already have a few ideas on how I can put this to good use on Project Cuba.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Adobe!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/thank-you-adobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 02:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/thank-you-adobe/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had a great journey together but it&amp;rsquo;s time to say goodbye!&amp;hellip; Although&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s your fault and let me explain why&amp;hellip;
Ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve started working professionally on the creative industry more than 10 years ago, Adobe software has been the standard by which every designer measured their software skills. For the most part this still holds true nowadays, but the tides are changing rapidly it and will probably be too overwhelming for Adobe to handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script Inspector 3 (Beta) Quick Review</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/script-inspector-3-beta-quick-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 18:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/script-inspector-3-beta-quick-review/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working with Unity on a Mac you are unfortunately stuck to the ugly, outdated and painfully sluggish, MonoDevelop. There are some alternatives like using Sublime, TextMate, or, if you&amp;rsquo;re on feeling adventurous, you can even use Visual Studio (with the amazing UnityVS) from a virtual machine. However, none of these options is really convenient since you either have to give up on most benefits of a true IDE or you have to use a resource hog VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Plugin — TimeScale Controller (Free)</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-plugin-timescale-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 16:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-plugin-timescale-controller/</guid>
      <description>One of the key aspects of the game I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on is trying to make all the animations blend nicely together. That blending is accomplished by the fantastic Spine which I vouched for in a previous blog post.
However, Spine does not (yet) have a way for you to test how animations transition to each other meaning I have to rely on how it looks during gameplay. Since my game is quite fast-paced, most transitions are fractions of a second which makes it really hard to see if they&amp;rsquo;re blending perfectly or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Quick Tips — Enum Description Extension Method</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-quick-tips-enum-description-extension-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 14:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-quick-tips-enum-description-extension-method/</guid>
      <description>While this tip is not Unity specific, it&amp;rsquo;s still very useful for all C# Unity devs out there.
Recently I needed to get a name/description out of a enum. After some digging around, I found this subject is far from consensual and there are dozens of different solutions to accomplish the same result. For me, by far, the simplest and cleanest way to do it is by using a cool feature in C# called extension methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity 2D Skeletal Animation</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-2d-skeletal-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 16:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-2d-skeletal-animation/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest draws, if not the biggest, of doing my own games is the opportunity to spend as much time on a feature as I feel is needed — not something you can say about most client projects where you have the constant pressure of a strict deadline on your shoulders. While most of the time, you just have to step back and realize when you&amp;rsquo;re pushing a certain feature or detail too further, sometimes you also need to bite the bullet and re-do some of your previous work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Quick Tips — Global Conditional Attributes</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-quick-tips-global-conditional-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 17:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-quick-tips-global-conditional-attributes/</guid>
      <description>A very useful trick you can do on your Unity projects is to setup some global conditional attributes. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how and what for in a very a simple example.
First go to your Player Settings (Edit &amp;gt; Project Settings &amp;gt; Player) and under the Other Settings tab, type &amp;ldquo;DEBUG&amp;rdquo; on the Scripting Define Symbols.
You can now in your scripts do something like:
[System.Diagnostics.Conditional(&amp;quot;DEBUG&amp;quot;)] void DrawRay(Vector2 start, Vector2 dir, Color color, float duration) { Debug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Quick Tips — Local Cache Server</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-quick-tips-cache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 22:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-quick-tips-cache-server/</guid>
      <description>After many years working with Unity, I&amp;rsquo;ve realised that one of the most overlooked features of the Unity&amp;rsquo;s Team License, by myself and other fellow developers, is the Cache Server.
Like the name says, what it basically does is caching your assets in order to make them load faster. This is particularly great if you&amp;rsquo;re working on a multi-platform game where you need to switch platforms constantly. As you all know, every time you do that Unity has to reimport all the assets, which can be a pretty painful depending on the size and number of resources on your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going public</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/going-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 22:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/going-public/</guid>
      <description>For the last several months, during my (very limited) free time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a game which started to form in my head ever since I visited the incredibly beautiful city of Havana, Cuba in October 2012.
I got enchanted by everything about it but especially its old charm - from the colourful 19th-century buildings to the imported american cars, the incredible white sand beaches and the overall good vibe of the cuban locals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restart 3.0!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/restart30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/restart30/</guid>
      <description>Hi again!
As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably figured out by now, my name is Luís Pedro Fonseca and I&amp;rsquo;m a game developer. You can learn more about me here.
This is my third introductory blog post (I&amp;rsquo;ve had two other blogs in the past who died horribly from abandonment) and strangely enough it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get easier. I hope to not make the same mistakes with this blog as I did before and I&amp;rsquo;m counting on you to help me out keeping this blog up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m an interactive developer from Porto, Portugal, with over a decade of experience on a multitude of technologies ranging from Flash to Objective-C, with a strong focus on Unity and gaming over the last several years. Certified SCRUM master with an expired certificate.
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a very wide range of projects for high-profiles companies such as FOX Broadcasting, Microsoft, RIOT Games, Dell, Dreamworks and many others. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start creating my own games and plugins and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share as much as possible here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please get in touch using the form below. Feel free to reach me through Twitter as well.
 .feedback-input { color:#3c3c3c; font-weight:500; font-size: 14px; border-radius: 0; background-color: #efefef; padding: 13px 13px 13px 54px; margin-bottom: 10px; width:100%; -webkit-box-sizing: border-box; -moz-box-sizing: border-box; -ms-box-sizing: border-box; box-sizing: border-box; border: 3px solid rgba(0,0,0,0); } #contact_name{ background-image: url(/images/contact-form/name.svg); background-size: 30px 30px; background-position: 11px 8px; background-repeat: no-repeat; } #contact_email{ background-image: url(/images/contact-form/email.svg); background-size: 30px 30px; background-position: 11px 8px; background-repeat: no-repeat; } #contact_comment{ background-image: url(/images/contact-form/comment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of a few of my best projects for the past several years.
Some projects are still under NDA so please don&amp;rsquo;t share this page publicly.
Dell The Great Xscape VR Client: Dell Inc.
Release Date: June 2018
Duration: 6 months
Role: Lead Developer
Technology: Unity, SteamVR, HTC Vive, UNet
Description: An escape room (in space) designed to introduce the players to Dell EMC products while at the same time having fun in a VR experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Cuba</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/project-cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/project-cuba/</guid>
      <description>This page will contain all the information regarding my upcoming game &amp;#8211; Project Cuba. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave you here with a promo image by my incredibly talented friend Adi Darda.
In the meantime, please have a look at the blog posts related to the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>