<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Procamera2d on Luís Pedro Fonseca</title>
    <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/categories/procamera2d/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Procamera2d on Luís Pedro Fonseca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/categories/procamera2d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unite Los Angeles 16</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unite-los-angeles-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unite-los-angeles-16/</guid>
      <description>It was with great pleasure and pride that I learnt that ProCamera2D got nominated to this year&amp;rsquo;s Unity Awards! The award cerimony took place in Los Angeles, on the first evening of the Unite 16 conference.
Unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t win, but being a finalist was more than I ever expected. The winner was Dungeon Architect. Congratulations to Code Respawn and all the other nominees! They were all amazing and I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to be part of this group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Custom Rect Editor</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-custom-rect-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/unity-custom-rect-editor/</guid>
      <description>One of the main goals of ProCamera2D&amp;rsquo;s new extension - Rooms - was to make it as user-friendly as possible.
Each room is basically a rectangle with some extra data to allow custom transitions. To make it easy to edit the rooms the user should be able to interact with them on the scene. However, Unity does not have a built-in rectangle (Rect) editor tool.
Gladly, Unity is very flexible and easy to extend, so I created a simple one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProCamera2D at GDC16</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-at-gdc16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-at-gdc16/</guid>
      <description>This year I had the honor to be invited to be part of the biggest game development conference in the world — the Game Developers Conference in San Francisco. The invite came from Unity and they were kind enough to offer me a kiosk, inside their gigantic mega-booth, where I could showcase my Unity camera plugin - ProCamera2D.
I also got two Expo passes for the 3 days and I even got to attend Unity&amp;rsquo;s own keynote at the Intercontinental hotel (amazing breakfast included!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProCamera2D turns 1!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-turns-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 09:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/procamera2d-turns-1/</guid>
      <description>My first commit for ProCamera2D was almost exactly 1 year ago, on January 20th 2015. It was officially released 6 months later.
Although it may sound weird to celebrate this, instead of the release date, for me it really marks a turning point. On that day I decided I was going to release my own product, no matter what, after years and years of exclusively working on clients&amp;rsquo; projects.
While I still work on clients&amp;rsquo; projects and I thoroughly enjoy it, there&amp;rsquo;s a deeper and more meaningful connection when the success and direction of a project is 100% under your responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Unity plugin is here!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/my-first-unity-plugin-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/my-first-unity-plugin-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Hi all, long time no talk.
For the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly busy between client work and working on my first Unity plugin. This plugin started out as a little tool that I extracted from Project Cuba, but ended up becoming a full-fledged 2D camera solution so I decided to turn it into a plugin and put it on the Asset Store.
  It ended up taking up a lot more time than I expected due to all the work I wasn&amp;rsquo;t anticipating, mostly marketing related.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>