<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Luís Pedro Fonseca</title>
    <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Luís Pedro Fonseca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New site engine — Hugo</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/new-site-engine-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/new-site-engine-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started with this blog/website, publishing a new post, updating some information or even tweaking its layout, has always been a chore.
This website was made with Wordpress because that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the standard when you&amp;rsquo;re planning to start a blog. Your host provider gives you a very convenient one-click install solution and you can be up and running in a matter of minutes. There are an infinite number of plugins for every possible use-case you can think of and even more themes to customize its look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Adobe!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/thank-you-adobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 02:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/thank-you-adobe/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had a great journey together but it&amp;rsquo;s time to say goodbye!&amp;hellip; Although&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s your fault and let me explain why&amp;hellip;
Ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve started working professionally on the creative industry more than 10 years ago, Adobe software has been the standard by which every designer measured their software skills. For the most part this still holds true nowadays, but the tides are changing rapidly it and will probably be too overwhelming for Adobe to handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restart 3.0!</title>
      <link>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/restart30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.luispedrofonseca.com/restart30/</guid>
      <description>Hi again!
As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably figured out by now, my name is Luís Pedro Fonseca and I&amp;rsquo;m a game developer. You can learn more about me here.
This is my third introductory blog post (I&amp;rsquo;ve had two other blogs in the past who died horribly from abandonment) and strangely enough it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get easier. I hope to not make the same mistakes with this blog as I did before and I&amp;rsquo;m counting on you to help me out keeping this blog up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
